Guide to the Center for AIDS photos and related materials MS 770
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Center for AIDS photos and related materials
1980-2009
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Williams, Tori
MS 770
1 Linear Feet (1 box)
The collection consists of photographic materials, compact discs, and momorabilia spanning the years 1980 to 2009.
Biographical / Historical
The Center for AIDS (CFA) opened its doors in 1995 with the goal of helping to shape research priorities and serving as an information resource for those living with AIDS. It is dedicated to gathering, interpreting, and making information available while furthering the national research agenda. The Center strives to keep both the Houston medical and affected coummunity informed, updated and involved in a search for a cure.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of one box of photographs, negatives, CDs, and memorabilia spanning the years 1980 to 2009.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was donated by the Center for AIDS via Tori Williams (community activist and co-founder of the oH Project) on July 12, 2018.
Arrangement
The materials in this collection have been arranged in four series: Series I: Photographs, Series II: Negatives, Series III: CDs, Series IV: Memorabilia
Index Terms
Subjects
Health care and medicine; AIDS (Disease) - Patients; AIDS (Disease); LGBTQ people
Subjects (Persons)
Williams, Tori
- Series I: Photographs
  - "70 Girls 70", 1980-12-05 (Box 1, Envelope 1)
  - Holiday event, 1997 (Box 1, Envelope 2)
  - Opening of Center, 1407 Hawthorne, 1998-08 (Box 1, Envelope 3)
  - Staff retreat, 1998-08 (Box 1, Envelope 4)
  - 11th Annual Conference on AIDS in America, 1999-04-30 (Box 1, Envelope 5)
  - "Chow-Down", 2000-05 (Box 1, Envelope 6)
  - at the Center, 2000-05 (Box 1, Envelope 7)
  - various events, 2000 (Box 1, Envelope 8)
  - "Ride for a Cure" party, 2002 (Box 1, Envelope 9)
  - Reception for Joel Martinez, 2003-03-20 (Box 1, Envelope 10)
  - House recital, 2003-05-08 (Box 1, Envelope 11)
  - "A Little Night Music", 2003 (Box 1, Envelope 12)
  - event, 2007-12 (Box 1, Envelope 13-14)
  - "Schmooze", 2008-12 (Box 1, Envelope 15)
  - offices, 1407 Hawthorne (Box 1, Envelope 16-17)
  - offices, Hollyfield St. (Box 1, Envelope 18)
  - staff, n.d & 1998-04 (Box 1, Envelope 19-20)
  - Board of Directors (Box 1, Envelope 21)
  - Jackson Hicks (Box 1, Envelope 22)
  - "Building America's Bridge" (Box 1, Envelope 23)
  - "Hug-a-Hunk" (1st fundraiser) (Box 1, Envelope 24)
  - Project Hope (Box 1, Envelope 25)
  - Emo's (Box 1, Envelope 26)
  - Holiday event (Box 1, Envelope 27)
  - Tour of offices/open house[?] (Box 1, Envelope 28)
  - Recognition party for Joel Martinez, co-founder of Center, 2003 (Box 1, Envelope 29)
  - unknown (Box 1, Envelope 30)
- Series II: Negatives
  - undated (Box 1, Envelope 31)
  - offices: 1407 Hawthorne (Box 1, Envelope 32-33)
  - Joel Martinez (Box 1, Envelope 34)
  - Benefactors (Box 1, Envelope 35)
- Series III: CDs
  - Photos, 2004 (Box 1, Envelope 36)
  - 70 Girls 70 rehearsal, 2004 (Box 1, Envelope 37)
  - AIDS walk, 2004, 2005, 2006 (Box 1, Envelope 38)
  - Event, 2005-12 (Box 1, Envelope 39)
  - AIDS walk, 2006 (Box 1, Envelope 40)
  - Party at Julie Greenwood's, 2006 (Box 1, Envelope 41)
  - Office files, 2006 (Box 1, Envelope 42)
  - Office files, 2007 (Box 1, Envelope 43)
  - Poster, flyer, 2007 (Box 1, Envelope 44)
  - Classroom, 2007 (Box 1, Envelope 45)
  - Development Committee, 2007 (Box 1, Envelope 46)
  - Annual reports, 2008 (Box 1, Envelope 47)
  - Statistics, 2008 (Box 1, Envelope 48)
  - Staff, 2008 (Box 1, Envelope 49)
  - AIDS walk, 2008 (Box 1, Envelope 50)
  - AIDS walk, 2009 (Box 1, Envelope 51)
- Series IV: Memorabilia
  - Guest book, 1996-2004 (Box 1)
  - American sterling silver teaspoon, Lunt silversmiths, Mount Vernon pattern ca. 1900 (Box 1)